Zara Fahar 263 London Road, Highbridge, Nowhereshire, XP9 8JQ zfahar99@gmail.com 07567567

Due to graduate in 2023, I have acquired technical knowledge and skills from my course as well as practical and business skills from my industrial year in a software company in Germany. I have used a range of languages, operating systems and development tools as well as experiencing the system development life cycle. Specialising in mobile technology, I am keen to develop as a graduate trainee in software development.

Education

University of Bedfordshire (2019-2023)

BSc Computer Science and Software Engineering with industrial year. Predicted 2:1.

Modules include object oriented programming, mobile applications, Al and systems development. Third-year industry placement: Mehrmann Technologies, Essen, Germany (2022).

Placement year individual project: Stock control systems for wholesale food suppliers.

Final-year group project: Development of a mobile application for the hospitality sector.

Highbridge College (2017-2019)

BTEC Level 3 ICT

A-level maths

Highbridge School (2012-2017)

7 GCSEs in English language, maths, science, German, IT, PE, history.

IT Skills

- Development tools: LabVIEW, MATLAB, Simulink, WINDEV/WEBDEV, OrCAD, MPLAB and ModelSim Packages: MS Office, Dreamweave and Photoshop
- Programming Languages: Java, C++, SQL, TLearn and HTML
- Operating Systems: Android, iOS, Windows and Linux

Other training/skills

- PRINCE2
- BCS Foundation Certificate in Systems Development
- Conversational German, including technical and business

Employment

Junior software developer, Mehrmann Technologies, Essen, Germany (2022)

- Systems analysis with clients to determine requirements talking to managers and staff and observing work practices throughout the supply chain
- Analysis of data including modelling
- Part of a software development team creating a stock control system linking mobile devices to warehouse systems
- Demonstrating prototypes to staff
- Field testing, implementation and evaluation
- Participating in final project reporting
- Contributing to English language documentation and training

Bar assistant, Ship and Crown, Luton (2020-2021)

- Serving customers
- Keeping bar area tidy and well-stocked
- Maintaining health and safety and food hygiene standards

Retail assistant, Primark, Highbridge (2017-2019)

- Tidying stock on the shop floor
- Restocking shelves and rails
- Serving customers at till points
- Dealing with customer queries on the shop floor

Sports and interests

- University of Bedfordshire Second XI Hockey Captain
- University of Bedfordshire Athletics Squad 800m and 1500m
- Highbridge College Hockey Team (winners of Midlands College Cup)
- Highbridge School Hockey First XI Captain
- Represented Nowhereshire in 1500m U16 and U18
- Running 10k and half marathon events raising over £6,500 for Highbridge Children's Hospice
- Organising and hosting charity comedy nights in aid of Highbridge Children's Hospice